<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rules>
  <rule>
    <key>S5042</key>
    <name>Expanding archive files is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Expanding archive files is security-sensitive. For example, expanding archive files has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-1263">CVE-2018-1263</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-16131">CVE-2018-16131</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>Applications that expand archive files (zip, tar, jar, war, 7z, ...) should verify the path where the archive's files are expanded and not trust
blindly the content of the archive. Archive's files should not be expanded outside of the root directory where the archive is supposed to be expanded.
Also, applications should control the size of the expanded data to not be a victim of Zip Bomb attack. Failure to do so could allow an attacker to use
a specially crafted archive that holds directory traversal paths (e.g. ../../attacker.sh) or the attacker could overload the file system, processors
or memory of the operating system where the archive is expanded making the target OS completely unusable.</p>
<p>This rule raises an issue when code handle archives. The goal is to guide security code reviews.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> there is no validation of the name of the archive entry </li>
  <li> there is no validation of the effective path where the archive entry is going to be expanded </li>
  <li> there is no validation of the size of the expanded archive entry </li>
  <li> there is no validation of the ratio between the compressed and uncompressed archive entry </li>
</ul>
<p>You are at risk if you answered yes to any of those questions.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<p>Validate the full path of the extracted file against the full path of the directory where files are expanded.</p>
<ul>
  <li> the canonical path of the expanded file must start with the canonical path of the directory where files are extracted. </li>
  <li> the name of the archive entry must not contain "..", i.e. reference to a parent directory. </li>
</ul>
<p>Stop extracting the archive if any of its entries has been tainted with a directory traversal path.</p>
<p>Define and control the ratio between compressed and uncompress bytes.</p>
<p>Define and control the maximum allowed expanded file size.</p>
<p>Count the number of file entries extracted from the archive and abort the extraction if their number is greater than a predefined threshold.</p>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
foreach (ZipArchiveEntry entry in archive.Entries)
{
    //  entry.FullName could contain parent directory references ".." and the destinationPath variable could become outside of the desired path
    string destinationPath = Path.GetFullPath(Path.Combine(path, entry.FullName));

    entry.ExtractToFile(destinationPath); // Sensitive, extracts the entry in a file

    Stream stream;
    stream = entry.Open(); // Sensitive, the entry is about to be extracted
}
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A1-Injection">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A1</a> - Injection </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/409.html">MITRE, CWE-409</a> - Improper Handling of Highly Compressed Data (Data Amplification)
  </li>
  <li> <a href="https://wiki.sei.cmu.edu/confluence/display/java/IDS04-J.+Safely+extract+files+from+ZipInputStream">CERT, IDS04-J.</a> - Safely
  extract files from ZipInputStream </li>
  <li> Snyk Research Team: <a href="https://snyk.io/research/zip-slip-vulnerability">Zip Slip Vulnerability</a> </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a1</tag>
    <remediationFunction>CONSTANT_ISSUE</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionBaseEffort>10min</remediationFunctionBaseEffort>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S4834</key>
    <name>Controlling permissions is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Controlling permissions is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-12999">CVE-2018-12999</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-10285">CVE-2018-10285</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2017-7455">CVE-2017-7455</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>Attackers can only damage what they have access to. Thus limiting their access is a good way to prevent them from wreaking havoc, but it has to be
done properly.</p>
<p>This rule flags code that controls the access to resources and actions or configures this access. The goal is to guide security code reviews.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> at least one accessed action or resource is security-sensitive. </li>
  <li> there is no access control in place or it does not cover all sensitive actions and resources. </li>
  <li> users have permissions they don't need. </li>
  <li> the access control is based on a user input or on some other unsafe data. </li>
  <li> permissions are difficult to remove or take a long time to be updated. </li>
</ul>
<p>You are at risk if you answered yes to the first question and any of the following ones.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<p>The first step is to restrict all sensitive actions to authenticated users.</p>
<p>Each user should have the lowest privileges possible. The access control granularity should match the sensitivity of each resource or action. The
more sensitive it is, the less people should have access to it. </p>
<p>Do not base the access control on a user input or on a value which might have been tampered with. For example, the developer should not read a
user's permissions from an HTTP cookie as it can be modified client-side.</p>
<p>Check that the access to each action and resource is properly restricted.</p>
<p>Enable administrators to swiftly remove permissions when necessary. This enables them to reduce the time an attacker can have access to your
systems when a breach occurs.</p>
<p>Log and monitor refused access requests as they can reveal an attack.</p>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
using System.Threading;
using System.Security.Permissions;
using System.Security.Principal;
using System.IdentityModel.Tokens;

class SecurityPrincipalDemo
{
    class MyIdentity : IIdentity // Sensitive, custom IIdentity implementations should be reviewed
    {
        // ...
    }

    class MyPrincipal : IPrincipal // Sensitive, custom IPrincipal implementations should be reviewed
    {
        // ...
    }
    [System.Security.Permissions.PrincipalPermission(SecurityAction.Demand, Role = "Administrators")] // Sensitive. The access restrictions enforced by this attribute should be reviewed.
    static void CheckAdministrator()
    {
        WindowsIdentity MyIdentity = WindowsIdentity.GetCurrent(); // Sensitive
        HttpContext.User = ...; // Sensitive: review all reference (set and get) to System.Web HttpContext.User
        AppDomain domain = AppDomain.CurrentDomain;
        domain.SetPrincipalPolicy(PrincipalPolicy.WindowsPrincipal); // Sensitive
        MyIdentity identity = new MyIdentity(); // Sensitive
        MyPrincipal MyPrincipal = new MyPrincipal(MyIdentity); // Sensitive
        Thread.CurrentPrincipal = MyPrincipal; // Sensitive
        domain.SetThreadPrincipal(MyPrincipal); // Sensitive

        // All instantiation of PrincipalPermission should be reviewed.
        PrincipalPermission principalPerm = new PrincipalPermission(null, "Administrators"); // Sensitive
        principalPerm.Demand();

        SecurityTokenHandler handler = ...;
        // Sensitive: this creates an identity.
        ReadOnlyCollection&lt;ClaimsIdentity&gt; identities = handler.ValidateToken(…);
    }

     // Sensitive: review how this function uses the identity and principal.
    void modifyPrincipal(MyIdentity identity, MyPrincipal principal)
    {
        // ...
    }
}
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A5-Broken_Access_Control">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A5</a> - Boken Access Control </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.sans.org/top25-software-errors/#cat3">SANS Top 25</a> - Porous Defenses </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>sans-top25-porous</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a5</tag>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S4829</key>
    <name>Reading the Standard Input is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Reading Standard Input is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2005-2337">CVE-2005-2337</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2017-11449">CVE-2017-11449</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>It is common for attackers to craft inputs enabling them to exploit software vulnerabilities. Thus any data read from the standard input (stdin)
can be dangerous and should be validated.</p>
<p>This rule flags code that reads from the standard input.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> data read from the standard input is not sanitized before being used. </li>
</ul>
<p>You are at risk if you answered yes to this question.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Input_Validation_Cheat_Sheet">Sanitize</a> all data read from the standard input before using it.</p>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
using System;
public class C
{
    public void Main()
    {
        Console.In; // Sensitive
        var code = Console.Read(); // Sensitive
        var keyInfo = Console.ReadKey(...); // Sensitive
        var text = Console.ReadLine(); // Sensitive
        Console.OpenStandardInput(...); // Sensitive
    }
}
</pre>
<h2>Exceptions</h2>
<p>This rule does not raise issues when the return value of the <code>Console.Read</code> <code>Console.ReadKey</code> or
<code>Console.ReadLine</code> methods is ignored.</p>
<pre>
using System;
public class C
{
    public void Main()
    {
        Console.ReadKey(...); // Return value is ignored
        Console.ReadLine(); // Return value is ignored
    }
}
</pre>
<h2>See:</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/20.html">MITRE, CWE-20</a> - Improper Input Validation </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S4823</key>
    <name>Using command line arguments is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Using command line arguments is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-7281">CVE-2018-7281</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-12326">CVE-2018-12326</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-3198">CVE-2011-3198</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>Command line arguments can be dangerous just like any other user input. They should never be used without being first validated and sanitized.</p>
<p>Remember also that any user can retrieve the list of processes running on a system, which makes the arguments provided to them visible. Thus
passing sensitive information via command line arguments should be considered as insecure.</p>
<p>This rule raises an issue when on every program entry points (<code>main</code> methods) when command line arguments are used. The goal is to guide
security code reviews.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> any of the command line arguments are used without being sanitized first. </li>
  <li> your application accepts sensitive information via command line arguments. </li>
</ul>
<p>If you answered yes to any of these questions you are at risk.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Input_Validation_Cheat_Sheet">Sanitize</a> all command line arguments before using them.</p>
<p>Any user or application can list running processes and see the command line arguments they were started with. There are safer ways of providing
sensitive information to an application than exposing them in the command line. It is common to write them on the process' standard input, or give the
path to a file containing the information.</p>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
namespace MyNamespace
{
    class Program
    {
        static void Main(string[] args) // Sensitive if there is a reference to "args" in the method.
        {
            string myarg = args[0];
            // ...
        }
    }
}
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A1-Injection">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A1</a> - Injection </li>
  <li> <a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/88.html">MITRE, CWE-88</a> - Argument Injection or Modification </li>
  <li> <a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/214.html">MITRE, CWE-214</a> - Information Exposure Through Process Environment </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.sans.org/top25-software-errors/#cat1">SANS Top 25</a> - Insecure Interaction Between Components </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a1</tag>
    <tag>sans-top25-insecure</tag>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S4818</key>
    <name>Using Sockets is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Using sockets is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2011-1785">CVE-2011-178</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2017-5645">CVE-2017-5645</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-6597">CVE-2018-6597</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>Sockets are vulnerable in multiple ways:</p>
<ul>
  <li> They enable a software to interact with the outside world. As this world is full of attackers it is necessary to check that they cannot receive
  sensitive information or inject dangerous input. </li>
  <li> The number of sockets is limited and can be exhausted. Which makes the application unresponsive to users who need additional sockets. </li>
</ul>
<p>This rules flags code that creates sockets. It matches only the direct use of sockets, not use through frameworks or high-level APIs such as the
use of http connections.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> sockets are created without any limit every time a user performs an action. </li>
  <li> input received from sockets is used without being sanitized. </li>
  <li> sensitive data is sent via sockets without being encrypted. </li>
</ul>
<p>You are at risk if you answered yes to any of these questions.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<ul>
  <li> In many cases there is no need to open a socket yourself. Use instead libraries and existing protocols. </li>
  <li> Encrypt all data sent if it is sensitive. Usually it is better to encrypt it even if the data is not sensitive as it might change later. </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Input_Validation_Cheat_Sheet">Sanitize</a> any input read from the socket. </li>
  <li> Limit the number of sockets a given user can create. Close the sockets as soon as possible. </li>
</ul>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
using System.Net.Sockets;

class TestSocket
{
    public static void Run()
    {
        // Sensitive
        Socket socket = new Socket(AddressFamily.InterNetwork, SocketType.Stream, ProtocolType.Tcp);

        // TcpClient and UdpClient simply abstract the details of creating a Socket
        TcpClient client = new TcpClient("example.com", 80); // Sensitive
        UdpClient listener = new UdpClient(80); // Sensitive
    }
}
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A3</a> - Sensitive Data Exposure
  </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/20">MITRE, CWE-20</a> - Improper Input Validation </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/400">MITRE, CWE-400</a> - Uncontrolled Resource Consumption ('Resource Exhaustion') </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/200">MITRE, CWE-200</a> - Information Exposure </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.sans.org/top25-software-errors/#cat2">SANS Top 25</a> - Risky Resource Management </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.sans.org/top25-software-errors/#cat3">SANS Top 25</a> - Porous Defenses </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>sans-top25-risky</tag>
    <tag>sans-top25-porous</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a3</tag>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S4792</key>
    <name>Configuring loggers is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Configuring loggers is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-0285">CVE-2018-0285</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2000-1127">CVE-2000-1127</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2017-15113">CVE-2017-15113</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2015-5742">CVE-2015-5742</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>Logs are useful before, during and after a security incident.</p>
<ul>
  <li> Attackers will most of the time start their nefarious work by probing the system for vulnerabilities. Monitoring this activity and stopping it
  is the first step to prevent an attack from ever happening. </li>
  <li> In case of a successful attack, logs should contain enough information to understand what damage an attacker may have inflicted. </li>
</ul>
<p>Logs are also a target for attackers because they might contain sensitive information. Configuring loggers has an impact on the type of information
logged and how they are logged.</p>
<p>This rule flags for review code that initiates loggers configuration. The goal is to guide security code reviews.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> unauthorized users might have access to the logs, either because they are stored in an insecure location or because the application gives
  access to them. </li>
  <li> the logs contain sensitive information on a production server. This can happen when the logger is in debug mode. </li>
  <li> the log can grow without limit. This can happen when additional information is written into logs every time a user performs an action and the
  user can perform the action as many times as he/she wants. </li>
  <li> the logs do not contain enough information to understand the damage an attacker might have inflicted. The loggers mode (info, warn, error)
  might filter out important information. They might not print contextual information like the precise time of events or the server hostname. </li>
  <li> the logs are only stored locally instead of being backuped or replicated. </li>
</ul>
<p>You are at risk if you answered yes to any of those questions.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<ul>
  <li> Check that your production deployment doesn't have its loggers in "debug" mode as it might write sensitive information in logs. </li>
  <li> Production logs should be stored in a secure location which is only accessible to system administrators. </li>
  <li> Configure the loggers to display all warnings, info and error messages. Write relevant information such as the precise time of events and the
  hostname. </li>
  <li> Choose log format which is easy to parse and process automatically. It is important to process logs rapidly in case of an attack so that the
  impact is known and limited. </li>
  <li> Check that the permissions of the log files are correct. If you index the logs in some other service, make sure that the transfer and the
  service are secure too. </li>
  <li> Add limits to the size of the logs and make sure that no user can fill the disk with logs. This can happen even when the user does not control
  the logged information. An attacker could just repeat a logged action many times. </li>
</ul>
<p>Remember that configuring loggers properly doesn't make them bullet-proof. Here is a list of recommendations explaining on how to use your
logs:</p>
<ul>
  <li> Don't log any sensitive information. This obviously includes passwords and credit card numbers but also any personal information such as user
  names, locations, etc... Usually any information which is protected by law is good candidate for removal. </li>
  <li> Sanitize all user inputs before writing them in the logs. This includes checking its size, content, encoding, syntax, etc... As for any user
  input, validate using whitelists whenever possible. Enabling users to write what they want in your logs can have many impacts. It could for example
  use all your storage space or compromise your log indexing service. </li>
  <li> Log enough information to monitor suspicious activities and evaluate the impact an attacker might have on your systems. Register events such as
  failed logins, successful logins, server side input validation failures, access denials and any important transaction. </li>
  <li> Monitor the logs for any suspicious activity. </li>
</ul>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<p><strong>.Net Core</strong>: configure programmatically</p>
<pre>
using System;
using System.Collections;
using System.Collections.Generic;
using Microsoft.AspNetCore.Builder;
using Microsoft.AspNetCore.Hosting;
using Microsoft.Extensions.Configuration;
using Microsoft.Extensions.DependencyInjection;
using Microsoft.Extensions.Logging;
using Microsoft.Extensions.Options;
using Microsoft.AspNetCore;

namespace MvcApp
{
    public class ProgramLogging
    {
        public static IWebHostBuilder CreateWebHostBuilder(string[] args) =&gt;
            WebHost.CreateDefaultBuilder(args)
                .ConfigureLogging((hostingContext, logging) =&gt; // Sensitive
                {
                    // ...
                })
                .UseStartup&lt;StartupLogging&gt;();
    }

    public class StartupLogging
    {
        public void ConfigureServices(IServiceCollection services)
        {
            services.AddLogging(logging =&gt; // Sensitive
            {
                // ...
            });
        }

        public void Configure(IApplicationBuilder app, IHostingEnvironment env, ILoggerFactory loggerFactory)
        {
            IConfiguration config = null;
            LogLevel level = LogLevel.Critical;
            Boolean includeScopes = false;
            Func&lt;string,Microsoft.Extensions.Logging.LogLevel,bool&gt; filter = null;
            Microsoft.Extensions.Logging.Console.IConsoleLoggerSettings consoleSettings = null;
            Microsoft.Extensions.Logging.AzureAppServices.AzureAppServicesDiagnosticsSettings azureSettings = null;
            Microsoft.Extensions.Logging.EventLog.EventLogSettings eventLogSettings = null;

            // An issue will be raised for each call to an ILoggerFactory extension methods adding loggers.
            loggerFactory.AddAzureWebAppDiagnostics(); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddAzureWebAppDiagnostics(azureSettings); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddConsole(); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddConsole(level); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddConsole(level, includeScopes); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddConsole(filter); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddConsole(filter, includeScopes); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddConsole(config); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddConsole(consoleSettings); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddDebug(); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddDebug(level); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddDebug(filter); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddEventLog(); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddEventLog(eventLogSettings); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddEventLog(level); // Sensitive
            loggerFactory.AddEventSourceLogger(); // Sensitive

            IEnumerable&lt;ILoggerProvider&gt; providers = null;
            LoggerFilterOptions filterOptions1 = null;
            IOptionsMonitor&lt;LoggerFilterOptions&gt; filterOptions2 = null;

            LoggerFactory factory = new LoggerFactory(); // Sensitive
            new LoggerFactory(providers); // Sensitive
            new LoggerFactory(providers, filterOptions1); // Sensitive
            new LoggerFactory(providers, filterOptions2); // Sensitive
        }
    }
}
</pre>
<p><strong>Log4Net</strong></p>
<pre>
using System;
using System.IO;
using System.Xml;
using log4net.Appender;
using log4net.Config;
using log4net.Repository;

namespace Logging
{
    class Log4netLogging
    {
        void Foo(ILoggerRepository repository, XmlElement element, FileInfo configFile, Uri configUri, Stream configStream,
        IAppender appender, params IAppender[] appenders) {
            log4net.Config.XmlConfigurator.Configure(repository); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.XmlConfigurator.Configure(repository, element); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.XmlConfigurator.Configure(repository, configFile); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.XmlConfigurator.Configure(repository, configUri); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.XmlConfigurator.Configure(repository, configStream); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.XmlConfigurator.ConfigureAndWatch(repository, configFile); // Sensitive

            log4net.Config.DOMConfigurator.Configure(); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.DOMConfigurator.Configure(repository); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.DOMConfigurator.Configure(element); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.DOMConfigurator.Configure(repository, element); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.DOMConfigurator.Configure(configFile); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.DOMConfigurator.Configure(repository, configFile); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.DOMConfigurator.Configure(configStream); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.DOMConfigurator.Configure(repository, configStream); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.DOMConfigurator.ConfigureAndWatch(configFile); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.DOMConfigurator.ConfigureAndWatch(repository, configFile); // Sensitive

            log4net.Config.BasicConfigurator.Configure(); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.BasicConfigurator.Configure(appender); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.BasicConfigurator.Configure(appenders); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.BasicConfigurator.Configure(repository); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.BasicConfigurator.Configure(repository, appender); // Sensitive
            log4net.Config.BasicConfigurator.Configure(repository, appenders); // Sensitive
        }
    }
}
</pre>
<p><strong>NLog</strong>: configure programmatically</p>
<pre>
namespace Logging
{
    class NLogLogging
    {
        void Foo(NLog.Config.LoggingConfiguration config) {
            NLog.LogManager.Configuration = config; // Sensitive, this changes the logging configuration.
        }
    }
}
</pre>
<p><strong>Serilog</strong></p>
<pre>
namespace Logging
{
    class SerilogLogging
    {
        void Foo() {
            new Serilog.LoggerConfiguration(); // Sensitive
        }
    }
}
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A3</a> - Sensitive Data Exposure
  </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A10-Insufficient_Logging%26Monitoring">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A10</a> - Insufficient
  Logging &amp; Monitoring </li>
  <li> <a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/532.html">MITRE, CWE-532</a> - Information Exposure Through Log Files </li>
  <li> <a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/117.html">MITRE, CWE-117</a> - Improper Output Neutralization for Logs </li>
  <li> <a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/778.html">MITRE, CWE-778</a> - Insufficient Logging </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.sans.org/top25-software-errors/#cat3">SANS Top 25</a> - Porous Defenses </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a10</tag>
    <tag>sans-top25-porous</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a3</tag>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S4790</key>
    <name>Hashing data is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Hashing data is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-9233">CVE-2018-9233</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2013-5097">CVE-2013-5097</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2007-1051">CVE-2007-1051</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>Cryptographic hash functions are used to uniquely identify information without storing their original form. When not done properly, an attacker can
steal the original information by guessing it (ex: with a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rainbow_table">rainbow table</a>), or replace the
original data with another one having the same hash.</p>
<p>This rule flags code that initiates hashing.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> the hashed value is used in a security context. </li>
  <li> the hashing algorithm you are using is known to have vulnerabilities. </li>
  <li> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salt_(cryptography)">salts</a> are not automatically generated and applied by the hashing function.
  </li>
  <li> any generated salts are cryptographically weak or not credential-specific. </li>
</ul>
<p>You are at risk if you answered yes to the first question and any of the following ones.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<ul>
  <li> for security related purposes, use only hashing algorithms which are <a
  href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Password_Storage_Cheat_Sheet">currently known to be strong</a>. Avoid using algorithms like MD5 and SHA1
  completely in security contexts. </li>
  <li> do not define your own hashing- or salt algorithms as they will most probably have flaws. </li>
  <li> do not use algorithms that compute too quickly, like SHA256, as it must remain beyond modern hardware capabilities to perform brute force and
  dictionary based attacks. </li>
  <li> use a hashing algorithm that generate its own salts as part of the hashing. If you generate your own salts, make sure that a cryptographically
  strong salt algorithm is used, that generated salts are credential-specific, and finally, that the salt is applied correctly before the hashing.
  </li>
  <li> save both the salt and the hashed value in the relevant database record; during future validation operations, the salt and hash can then be
  retrieved from the database. The hash is recalculated with the stored salt and the value being validated, and the result compared to the stored
  hash. </li>
  <li> the strength of hashing algorithms often decreases over time as hardware capabilities increase. Check regularly that the algorithms you are
  using are still considered secure. If needed, rehash your data using a stronger algorithm. </li>
</ul>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
using System.Security.Cryptography;

void ComputeHash()
{
    // Review all instantiations of classes that inherit from HashAlgorithm, for example:
    HashAlgorithm hashAlgo = HashAlgorithm.Create(); // Sensitive
    HashAlgorithm hashAlgo2 = HashAlgorithm.Create("SHA1"); // Sensitive
    SHA1 sha = new SHA1CryptoServiceProvider(); // Sensitive
    MD5 md5 = new MD5CryptoServiceProvider(); // Sensitive
    // ...
}

class MyHashAlgorithm : HashAlgorithm // Sensitive
{
    // ...
}
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A3</a> - Sensitive Data Exposure
  </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A6-Security_Misconfiguration">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A6</a> - Security
  Misconfiguration </li>
  <li> <a href="https://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/916.html">MITRE, CWE-916</a> - Use of Password Hash With Insufficient Computational Effort
  </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/759.html">MITRE, CWE-759</a> - Use of a One-Way Hash without a Salt </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/760.html">MITRE, CWE-760</a> - Use of a One-Way Hash with a Predictable Salt </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.sans.org/top25-software-errors/#cat3">SANS Top 25</a> - Porous Defenses </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>spring</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a6</tag>
    <tag>sans-top25-porous</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a3</tag>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S4787</key>
    <name>Encrypting data is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Encrypting data is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2017-7902">CVE-2017-7902</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-1378">CVE-2006-1378</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2003-1376">CVE-2003-1376</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>Proper encryption requires both the encryption algorithm and the key to be strong. Obviously the private key needs to remain secret and be renewed
regularly. However these are not the only means to defeat or weaken an encryption.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>This rule flags function calls that initiate encryption/decryption. The goal is to guide security code reviews.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> the private key might not be random, strong enough or the same key is reused for a long long time. </li>
  <li> the private key might be compromised. It can happen when it is stored in an unsafe place or when it was transferred in an unsafe manner. </li>
  <li> the key exchange is made without properly authenticating the receiver. </li>
  <li> the encryption algorithm is not strong enough for the level of protection required. Note that encryption algorithms strength decreases as time
  passes. </li>
  <li> the chosen encryption library is deemed unsafe. </li>
  <li> a nonce is used, and the same value is reused multiple times, or the nonce is not random. </li>
  <li> the RSA algorithm is used, and it does not incorporate an Optimal Asymmetric Encryption Padding (OAEP), which might weaken the encryption.
  </li>
  <li> the CBC (Cypher Block Chaining) algorithm is used for encryption, and it's IV (Initialization Vector) is not generated using a secure random
  algorithm, or it is reused. </li>
  <li> the Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) encryption algorithm is used with an unsecure mode. See the recommended practices for more information.
  </li>
</ul>
<p>You are at risk if you answered yes to any of those questions.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<ul>
  <li> Generate encryption keys using secure random algorithms. </li>
  <li> When generating cryptographic keys (or key pairs), it is important to use a key length that provides enough entropy against brute-force
  attacks. For the Blowfish algorithm the key should be at least 128 bits long, while for the RSA algorithm it should be at least 2048 bits long.
  </li>
  <li> Regenerate the keys regularly. </li>
  <li> Always store the keys in a safe location and transfer them only over safe channels. </li>
  <li> If there is an exchange of cryptographic keys, check first the identity of the receiver. </li>
  <li> Only use strong encryption algorithms. Check regularly that the algorithm is still deemed secure. It is also imperative that they are
  implemented correctly. Use only encryption libraries which are deemed secure. Do not define your own encryption algorithms as they will most
  probably have flaws. </li>
  <li> When a nonce is used, generate it randomly every time. </li>
  <li> When using the RSA algorithm, incorporate an Optimal Asymmetric Encryption Padding (OAEP). </li>
  <li> When CBC is used for encryption, the IV must be random and unpredictable. Otherwise it exposes the encrypted value to crypto-analysis attacks
  like "Chosen-Plaintext Attacks". Thus a secure random algorithm should be used. An IV value should be associated to one and only one encryption
  cycle, because the IV's purpose is to ensure that the same plaintext encrypted twice will yield two different ciphertexts. </li>
  <li> The Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) encryption algorithm can be used with various modes. Galois/Counter Mode (GCM) with no padding should be
  preferred to the following combinations which are not secured:
    <ul>
      <li> Electronic Codebook (ECB) mode: Under a given key, any given plaintext block always gets encrypted to the same ciphertext block. Thus, it
      does not hide data patterns well. In some senses, it doesn't provide serious message confidentiality, and it is not recommended for use in
      cryptographic protocols at all. </li>
      <li> Cipher Block Chaining (CBC) with PKCS#5 padding (or PKCS#7) is susceptible to padding oracle attacks. </li>
    </ul> </li>
</ul>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
using System;
using System.Security.Cryptography;

namespace MyNamespace
{
    public class MyClass
    {
        public void Main()
        {
            Byte[] data = {1,1,1};

            RSA myRSA = RSA.Create();
            RSAEncryptionPadding padding = RSAEncryptionPadding.CreateOaep(HashAlgorithmName.SHA1);
            // Review all base RSA class' Encrypt/Decrypt calls
            myRSA.Encrypt(data, padding); // Sensitive
            myRSA.EncryptValue(data); // Sensitive
            myRSA.Decrypt(data, padding); // Sensitive
            myRSA.DecryptValue(data); // Sensitive

            RSACryptoServiceProvider myRSAC = new RSACryptoServiceProvider();
            // Review the use of any TryEncrypt/TryDecrypt and specific Encrypt/Decrypt of RSA subclasses.
            myRSAC.Encrypt(data, false); // Sensitive
            myRSAC.Decrypt(data, false); // Sensitive
            int written;
            myRSAC.TryEncrypt(data, Span&lt;byte&gt;.Empty, padding, out written); // Sensitive
            myRSAC.TryDecrypt(data, Span&lt;byte&gt;.Empty, padding, out written); // Sensitive

            byte[] rgbKey = {1,2,3};
            byte[] rgbIV = {4,5,6};
            SymmetricAlgorithm rijn = SymmetricAlgorithm.Create();
            // Review the creation of Encryptors from any SymmetricAlgorithm instance.
            rijn.CreateEncryptor(); // Sensitive
            rijn.CreateEncryptor(rgbKey, rgbIV); // Sensitive
            rijn.CreateDecryptor(); // Sensitive
            rijn.CreateDecryptor(rgbKey, rgbIV); // Sensitive
        }

        public class MyCrypto : System.Security.Cryptography.AsymmetricAlgorithm // Sensitive
        {
            // ...
        }

        public class MyCrypto2 : System.Security.Cryptography.SymmetricAlgorithm // Sensitive
        {
            // ...
        }
    }
}
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A3</a> - Sensitive Data Exposure
  </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A6-Security_Misconfiguration">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A6</a> - Security
  Misconfiguration </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/321.html">MITRE, CWE-321</a> - Use of Hard-coded Cryptographic Key </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/322.html">MITRE, CWE-322</a> - Key Exchange without Entity Authentication </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/323.html">MITRE, CWE-323</a> - Reusing a Nonce, Key Pair in Encryption </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/324.html">MITRE, CWE-324</a> - Use of a Key Past its Expiration Date </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/325.html">MITRE, CWE-325</a> - Missing Required Cryptographic Step </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/326.html">MITRE, CWE-326</a> - Inadequate Encryption Strength </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/327.html">MITRE, CWE-327</a> - Use of a Broken or Risky Cryptographic Algorithm </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/522.html">MITRE, CWE-522</a> - Insufficiently Protected Credentials </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.sans.org/top25-software-errors/#cat3">SANS Top 25</a> - Porous Defenses </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a6</tag>
    <tag>sans-top25-porous</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a3</tag>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S4784</key>
    <name>Using regular expressions is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Using regular expressions is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2017-16021">CVE-2017-16021</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-13863">CVE-2018-13863</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>Evaluating regular expressions against input strings is potentially an extremely CPU-intensive task. Specially crafted regular expressions such as
<code>(a+)+s</code> will take several seconds to evaluate the input string <code>aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaabs</code>. The problem is that with
every additional <code>a</code> character added to the input, the time required to evaluate the regex doubles. However, the equivalent regular
expression, <code>a+s</code> (without grouping) is efficiently evaluated in milliseconds and scales linearly with the input size.</p>
<p>Evaluating such regular expressions opens the door to <a
href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Regular_expression_Denial_of_Service_-_ReDoS">Regular expression Denial of Service (ReDoS)</a> attacks. In the
context of a web application, attackers can force the web server to spend all of its resources evaluating regular expressions thereby making the
service inaccessible to genuine users.</p>
<p>This rule flags any execution of a hardcoded regular expression which has at least 3 characters and at least two instances of any of the following
characters: <code>*+{</code>.</p>
<p>Example: <code>(a+)*</code></p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> the executed regular expression is sensitive and a user can provide a string which will be analyzed by this regular expression. </li>
  <li> your regular expression engine performance decrease with specially crafted inputs and regular expressions. </li>
</ul>
<p>You may be at risk if you answered yes to any of those questions.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<p>Check whether your regular expression engine (the algorithm executing your regular expression) has any known vulnerabilities. Search for
vulnerability reports mentioning the one engine you're are using.</p>
<p>If the regular expression is vulnerable to ReDos attacks, mitigate the risk by using a "match timeout" to limit the time spent running the regular
expression.</p>
<p>Remember also that a ReDos attack is possible if a user-provided regular expression is executed. This rule won't detect this kind of injection.</p>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
using System;
using System.Collections.Generic;
using System.Linq;
using System.Runtime.Serialization;
using System.Text.RegularExpressions;
using System.Web;

namespace N
{
    public class RegularExpression
    {
        void Foo(RegexOptions options, TimeSpan matchTimeout, string input,
                 string replacement, MatchEvaluator evaluator)
        {
            // All the following instantiations are Sensitive.
            new System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex("(a+)+");
            new System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex("(a+)+", options);
            new System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex("(a+)+", options, matchTimeout);

            // All the following static methods are Sensitive.
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.IsMatch(input, "(a+)+");
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.IsMatch(input, "(a+)+", options);
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.IsMatch(input, "(a+)+", options, matchTimeout);

            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Match(input, "(a+)+");
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Match(input, "(a+)+", options);
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Match(input, "(a+)+", options, matchTimeout);

            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Matches(input, "(a+)+");
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Matches(input, "(a+)+", options);
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Matches(input, "(a+)+", options, matchTimeout);

            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Replace(input, "(a+)+", evaluator);
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Replace(input, "(a+)+", evaluator, options);
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Replace(input, "(a+)+", evaluator, options, matchTimeout);
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Replace(input, "(a+)+", replacement);
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Replace(input, "(a+)+", replacement, options);
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Replace(input, "(a+)+", replacement, options, matchTimeout);

            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Split(input, "(a+)+");
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Split(input, "(a+)+", options);
            System.Text.RegularExpressions.Regex.Split(input, "(a+)+", options, matchTimeout);
        }
    }
}
</pre>
<h2>Exceptions</h2>
<p>Some corner-case regular expressions will not raise an issue even though they might be vulnerable. For example: <code>(a|aa)+</code>,
<code>(a|a?)+</code>.</p>
<p>It is a good idea to test your regular expression if it has the same pattern on both side of a "<code>|</code>".</p>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A1-Injection">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A1</a> - Injection </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Regular_expression_Denial_of_Service_-_ReDoS">MITRE, CWE-624</a> - Executable Regular Expression Error
  </li>
  <li> OWASP Regular expression Denial of Service - ReDoS </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a1</tag>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S4507</key>
    <name>Delivering code in production with debug features activated is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Delivering code in production with debug features activated is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-1999007">CVE-2018-1999007</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2015-5306">CVE-2015-5306</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2013-2006">CVE-2013-2006</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>An application's debug features enable developers to find bugs more easily. It often gives access to detailed information on both the system
running the application and users. Sometime it even enables the execution of custom commands. Thus deploying on production servers an application
which has debug features activated is extremely dangerous.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> the code or configuration enabling the application debug features is deployed on production servers. </li>
  <li> the application runs by default with debug features activated. </li>
</ul>
<p>You are at risk if you answered yes to any of these questions.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<p>Do not enable debug features on production servers.</p>
<p>The .Net Core framework offers multiple features which help during debug.
<code>Microsoft.AspNetCore.Builder.IApplicationBuilder.UseDeveloperExceptionPage</code> and
<code>Microsoft.AspNetCore.Builder.IApplicationBuilder.UseDatabaseErrorPage</code> are two of them. Make sure that those features are disabled in
production.</p>
<p> Use <code>if (env.IsDevelopment())</code> to disable debug code.</p>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<p>This rule raises issues when the following .Net Core methods are called:
<code>Microsoft.AspNetCore.Builder.IApplicationBuilder.UseDeveloperExceptionPage</code>,
<code>Microsoft.AspNetCore.Builder.IApplicationBuilder.UseDatabaseErrorPage</code>. No Issue is raised when those calls are disabled by <code>if
(env.IsDevelopment())</code>.</p>
<pre>
using Microsoft.AspNetCore.Builder;
using Microsoft.AspNetCore.Hosting;

namespace mvcApp
{
    public class Startup2
    {
        public void Configure(IApplicationBuilder app, IHostingEnvironment env)
        {
            if (env.IsDevelopment())
            {
                // The following calls are ok because they are disabled in production
                app.UseDeveloperExceptionPage();
                app.UseDatabaseErrorPage();
            }
            // Those calls are Sensitive because it seems that they will run in production
            app.UseDeveloperExceptionPage(); // Sensitive
            app.UseDatabaseErrorPage(); // Sensitive
        }
    }
}

</pre>
<h2>Exceptions</h2>
<p>This rule does not analyze configuration files. Make sure that debug mode is not enabled by default in those files.</p>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A3</a> - Sensitive Data Exposure
  </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/489.html">MITRE, CWE-489</a> - Leftover Debug Code </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/215.html">MITRE, CWE-215</a> - Information Exposure Through Debug Information </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a3</tag>
    <remediationFunction>CONSTANT_ISSUE</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionBaseEffort>1min</remediationFunctionBaseEffort>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S3011</key>
    <name>Changing or bypassing accessibility is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Changing or bypassing accessibility is security-sensitive. For example, it has led in the past to the following vulnerability:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2012-4681">CVE-2012-4681</a> </li>
</ul>
<p><code>private</code> methods were made <code>private</code> for a reason, and the same is true of every other visibility level. Altering or
bypassing the accessibility of classes, methods, or fields violates the encapsulation principle and could introduce security holes.</p>
<p>This rule raises an issue when reflection is used to change the visibility of a class, method or field, and when it is used to directly update a
field value.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> there is a good reason to override the existing accessibility level of the method/field. This is very rarely the case. Accessing hidden fields
  and methods will make your code unstable as they are not part of the public API and may change in future versions. </li>
  <li> this method is called by untrusted code. <strong>*</strong> </li>
  <li> it is possible to modify or bypass the accessibility of sensitive methods or fields using this code. <strong>*</strong> </li>
</ul>
<p><strong>*</strong> You are at risk if you answered yes to those questions.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<p>Don't change or bypass the accessibility of any method or field if possible.</p>
<p>If untrusted code can execute this method, make sure that it cannot decide which method or field's accessibility can be modified or bypassed.</p>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
using System.Reflection;

Type dynClass = Type.GetType("MyInternalClass");
// Sensitive. Using BindingFlags.NonPublic will return non-public members
BindingFlags bindingAttr = BindingFlags.NonPublic | BindingFlags.Static;
MethodInfo dynMethod = dynClass.GetMethod("mymethod", bindingAttr);
object result = dynMethod.Invoke(dynClass, null);
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A3</a> - Sensitive Data Exposure
  </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.securecoding.cert.org/confluence/x/3YEVAQ">CERT, SEC05-J.</a> - Do not use reflection to increase accessibility of
  classes, methods, or fields </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>owasp-a3</tag>
    <remediationFunction>CONSTANT_ISSUE</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionBaseEffort>30min</remediationFunctionBaseEffort>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S2255</key>
    <name>Writing cookies is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Using cookies is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-11639">CVE-2018-11639</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2016-6537">CVE-2016-6537</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>Attackers can use widely-available tools to read cookies, sensitive information written by the server will be exposed.</p>
<p>This rule flags code that writes cookies.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> sensitive information is stored inside the cookie. </li>
</ul>
<p>You are at risk if you answered yes to this question.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<p>Cookies should only be used to manage the user session. The best practice is to keep all user-related information server-side and link them to the
user session, never sending them to the client. In a very few corner cases, cookies can be used for non-sensitive information that need to live longer
than the user session.</p>
<p>Do not try to encode sensitive information in a non human-readable format before writing them in a cookie. The encoding can be reverted and the
original information will be exposed.</p>
<p>Using cookies only for session IDs doesn't make them secure. Follow <a
href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Session_Management_Cheat_Sheet#Cookies">OWASP best practices</a> when you configure your cookies.</p>
<p>As a side note, every information read from a cookie should be <a
href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Input_Validation_Cheat_Sheet">Sanitized</a>.</p>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
// === .Net Framework ===

HttpCookie myCookie = new HttpCookie("UserSettings");
myCookie["CreditCardNumber"] = "1234 1234 1234 1234"; // Sensitive; sensitive data stored
myCookie.Values["password"] = "5678"; // Sensitive
myCookie.Value = "mysecret"; // Sensitive
...
Response.Cookies.Add(myCookie);


// === .Net Core ===

Response.Headers.Add("Set-Cookie", ...); // Sensitive
Response.Cookies.Append("mykey", "myValue"); // Sensitive
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A3</a> - Sensitive Data Exposure
  </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/312.html">MITRE, CWE-312</a> - Cleartext Storage of Sensitive Information </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/315.html">MITRE, CWE-315</a> - Cleartext Storage of Sensitive Information in a Cookie </li>
  <li> <a href="https://wiki.sei.cmu.edu/confluence/display/java/FIO52-J.+Do+not+store+unencrypted+sensitive+information+on+the+client+side">CERT,
  FIO52-J.</a> - Do not store unencrypted sensitive information on the client side </li>
  <li> Derived from FindSecBugs rule <a href="https://find-sec-bugs.github.io/bugs.htm#COOKIE_USAGE">COOKIE_USAGE</a> </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>MINOR</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>sans-top25-porous</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a3</tag>
    <remediationFunction>CONSTANT_ISSUE</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionBaseEffort>5min</remediationFunctionBaseEffort>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S2245</key>
    <name>Using pseudorandom number generators (PRNGs) is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Using pseudorandom number generators (PRNGs) is security-sensitive. For example, it has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<p> * <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2013-6386">CVE-2013-6386</a></p>
<p> * <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-3419">CVE-2006-3419</a></p>
<p> * <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2008-4102">CVE-2008-4102</a></p>
<p>When software generates predictable values in a context requiring unpredictability, it may be possible for an attacker to guess the next value that
will be generated, and use this guess to impersonate another user or access sensitive information.</p>
<p>As the <code>System.Random</code> class relies on a pseudorandom number generator, it should not be used for security-critical applications or for
protecting sensitive data. In such context, the <code>System.Cryptography.RandomNumberGenerator</code> class which relies on a cryptographically
strong random number generator (RNG) should be used in place.</p>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> the code using the generated value requires it to be unpredictable. It is the case for all encryption mechanisms or when a secret value, such
  as a password, is hashed. </li>
  <li> the function you use generates a value which can be predicted (pseudo-random). </li>
  <li> the generated value is used multiple times. </li>
  <li> an attacker can access the generated value. </li>
</ul>
<p>You are at risk if you answered yes to the first question and any of the following ones.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<ul>
  <li> Only use random number generators which are <a
  href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Cryptographic_Storage_Cheat_Sheet#Rule_-_Use_strong_random_numbers">recommended by OWASP</a> or any other
  trusted organization. </li>
  <li> Use the generated random values only once. </li>
  <li> You should not expose the generated random value. If you have to store it, make sure that the database or file is secure. </li>
</ul>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
var random = new Random(); // Sensitive use of Random
byte[] data = new byte[16];
random.NextBytes(data);
return BitConverter.ToString(data); // Check if this value is used for hashing or encryption
</pre>
<h2>Compliant Solution</h2>
<pre>
using System.Security.Cryptography;
...
var randomGenerator = RandomNumberGenerator.Create(); // Compliant for security-sensitive use cases
byte[] data = new byte[16];
randomGenerator.GetBytes(data);
return BitConverter.ToString(data);
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A3</a> - Sensitive Data Exposure
  </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/338.html">MITRE, CWE-338</a> - Use of Cryptographically Weak Pseudo-Random Number Generator
  (PRNG) </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/330.html">MITRE, CWE-330</a> - Use of Insufficiently Random Values </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/326.html">MITRE, CWE-326</a> - Inadequate Encryption Strength </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.securecoding.cert.org/confluence/x/mAFqAQ">CERT, MSC02-J.</a> - Generate strong random numbers </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.securecoding.cert.org/confluence/x/qw4">CERT, MSC30-C.</a> - Do not use the rand() function for generating pseudorandom
  numbers </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.securecoding.cert.org/confluence/x/WYIyAQ">CERT, MSC50-CPP.</a> - Do not use std::rand() for generating pseudorandom
  numbers </li>
  <li> Derived from FindSecBugs rule <a href="http://h3xstream.github.io/find-sec-bugs/bugs.htm#PREDICTABLE_RANDOM">Predictable Pseudo Random Number
  Generator</a> </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a3</tag>
    <remediationFunction>CONSTANT_ISSUE</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionBaseEffort>10min</remediationFunctionBaseEffort>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S2092</key>
    <name>Creating cookies without the "secure" flag is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>The "secure" attribute prevents cookies from being sent over plaintext connections such as HTTP, where they would be easily eavesdropped upon.
Instead, cookies with the secure attribute are only sent over encrypted HTTPS connections.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<ul>
  <li> set the field <code>Secure</code> to <code>true</code> on the <code>HttpCookie</code> object </li>
</ul>
<h2>Noncompliant Code Example</h2>
<pre>
HttpCookie myCookie = new HttpCookie("UserSettings");
myCookie.Secure = false; // Noncompliant; explicitly set to false
...
Response.Cookies.Add(myCookie);
</pre>
<pre>
HttpCookie myCookie = new HttpCookie("UserSettings"); // Noncompliant; the default value of 'Secure' is used (=false)
...
Response.Cookies.Add(myCookie);
</pre>
<h2>Compliant Solution</h2>
<pre>
HttpCookie myCookie = new HttpCookie("UserSettings");
myCookie.Secure = true; // Compliant
...
Response.Cookies.Add(myCookie);
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A2-Broken_Authentication">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A2</a> - Broken Authentication </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A3</a> - Sensitive Data Exposure
  </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/311">MITRE, CWE-311</a> - Missing Encryption of Sensitive Data </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/315">MITRE, CWE-315</a> - Cleartext Storage of Sensitive Information in a Cookie </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/614">MITRE, CWE-614</a> - Sensitive Cookie in HTTPS Session Without 'Secure' Attribute </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.sans.org/top25-software-errors/#cat3">SANS Top 25</a> - Porous Defenses </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>MINOR</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>sans-top25-porous</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a2</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a3</tag>
    <remediationFunction>CONSTANT_ISSUE</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionBaseEffort>5min</remediationFunctionBaseEffort>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S2077</key>
    <name>Formatting SQL queries is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Formatting strings used as SQL queries is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-9019">CVE-2018-9019</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2018-7318">CVE-2018-7318</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2017-5611">CVE-2017-5611</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>SQL queries often need to use a hardcoded SQL string with a dynamic parameter coming from a user request. Formatting a string to add those
parameters to the request is a bad practice as it can result in an <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/SQL_Injection">SQL injection</a>. The safe
way to add parameters to a SQL query is to use SQL binding mechanisms.</p>
<p>This rule flags the execution of SQL queries which are built using formatting of strings, even if there is no injection. This rule does not detect
SQL injections. The goal is to guide security code reviews and to prevent a common bad practice.</p>
<p>The following specific method signatures are tested:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <code>System.Data.SqlClient.SqlCommand.SqlCommand(string, ...)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.SqlClient.SqlDataAdapter.SqlDataAdapter(string, ...)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.Odbc.OdbcCommand.OdbcCommand(string, ...)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.Odbc.OdbcDataAdapter.OdbcDataAdapter(string, ...)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.SqlServerCe.SqlCeCommand.SqlCeCommand(string, ...)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.SqlServerCe.SqlCeDataAdapter.SqlCeDataAdapter(string, ...)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.OracleClient.OracleCommand.OracleCommand(string, ...)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.OracleClient.OracleDataAdapter.OracleDataAdapter(string, ...)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>Microsoft.EntityFrameworkCore.RelationalDatabaseFacadeExtensions.ExecuteSqlCommand(...)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>Microsoft.EntityFrameworkCore.RelationalDatabaseFacadeExtensions.ExecuteSqlCommandAsync(...)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>Microsoft.EntityFrameworkCore.RelationalQueryableExtensions.FromSql&lt;TEntity&gt;(System.Linq.IQueryable&lt;TEntity&gt;,
  System.FormattableString)</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.SqlClient.SqlCommand.CommandText.set</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.Odbc.OdbcCommand.CommandText.set</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.SqlServerCe.SqlCeCommand.CommandText.set</code> </li>
  <li> <code>System.Data.OracleClient.OracleCommand.CommandText.set</code> </li>
</ul>
<p>The following formatting methods will raise an issue:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <code>String.Concat</code> </li>
  <li> <code>String.Format</code> </li>
  <li> <code>FormattableString</code>, with some exceptions (see the Exceptions section) </li>
</ul>
<h2>Ask Yourself Whether</h2>
<ul>
  <li> the SQL query is built using string formatting technics, such as concatenating variables. </li>
  <li> some of the values are coming from an untrusted source and are not sanitized. </li>
</ul>
<p>You may be at risk if you answered yes to this question.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<ul>
  <li> Avoid building queries manually using formatting technics. If you do it anyway, do not include user input in this building process. </li>
  <li> Use <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Query_Parameterization_Cheat_Sheet">parameterized queries, prepared statements, or stored
  procedures</a> whenever possible. </li>
  <li> You may also use ORM frameworks such as Hibernate which, if used correctly, reduce injection risks. </li>
  <li> Avoid executing SQL queries containing unsafe input in stored procedures or functions. </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Input_Validation_Cheat_Sheet">Sanitize</a> every unsafe input. </li>
</ul>
<p>You can also reduce the impact of an attack by using a database account with low privileges.</p>
<h2>Sensitive Code Example</h2>
<pre>
member this.Foo(context:DbContext, query:string, param:string) =
    let sensitiveQuery = String.Concat(query, param)
    context.Database.ExecuteSqlCommand(sensitiveQuery) // Sensitive
    context.Query&lt;User&gt;().FromSql(sensitiveQuery) // Sensitive

    context.Database.ExecuteSqlCommand(sprintf "SELECT * FROM mytable WHERE mycol=%s" param) // Sensitive
    let query = sprintf "SELECT * FROM mytable WHERE mycol=%s" param
    context.Database.ExecuteSqlCommand(query) // Sensitive

member this.Bar(connection:SqlConnection, param:string) =
    let sensitiveQuery = string.Format("INSERT INTO Users (name) VALUES (\"{0}\")", param)
    let command = SqlCommand(sensitiveQuery) // Sensitive

    command.CommandText &lt;- sensitiveQuery // Sensitive

    let adapter = new SqlDataAdapter(sensitiveQuery, connection) // Sensitive
</pre>
<h2>Exceptions</h2>
<p>No issue will be raised in the following cases:</p>
<ul>
  <li> When the SQL query is a FormattableString provided <strong>directly</strong> to <code>ExecuteSqlCommand</code>,
  <code>ExecuteSqlCommandAsync</code> or <code>FromSql</code>. In this case the FormattableString is automatically converted to a parametrized query.
  This feature was added in Entity Framework Core 2.0. See <a
  href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/ef/core/what-is-new/ef-core-2.0#string-interpolation-in-fromsql-and-executesqlcommand">Entity Framework's
  documentation</a> for more information. </li>
</ul>
<pre>
member this.Foo(context:DbContext, value:string) =
{
    context.Database.ExecuteSqlCommand("SELECT * FROM mytable") // No issue raised. The query is hard-coded. Thus no injection is possible.
    context.Database.ExecuteSqlCommand(sprintf "SELECT * FROM mytable WHERE mycol=%s" value) // Sensitive
}
</pre>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A1-Injection">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A1</a> - Injection </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/89">MITRE, CWE-89</a> - Improper Neutralization of Special Elements used in an SQL Command </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/564.html">MITRE, CWE-564</a> - SQL Injection: Hibernate </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/20.html">MITRE, CWE-20</a> - Improper Input Validation </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cwe.mitre.org/data/definitions/943.html">MITRE, CWE-943</a> - Improper Neutralization of Special Elements in Data Query Logic
  </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.securecoding.cert.org/confluence/x/PgIRAg">CERT, IDS00-J.</a> - Prevent SQL injection </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.sans.org/top25-software-errors/#cat1">SANS Top 25</a> - Insecure Interaction Between Components </li>
  <li> Derived from FindSecBugs rules <a href="http://h3xstream.github.io/find-sec-bugs/bugs.htm#SQL_INJECTION_JPA">Potential SQL/JPQL Injection
  (JPA)</a>, <a href="http://h3xstream.github.io/find-sec-bugs/bugs.htm#SQL_INJECTION_JDO">Potential SQL/JDOQL Injection (JDO)</a>, <a
  href="http://h3xstream.github.io/find-sec-bugs/bugs.htm#SQL_INJECTION_HIBERNATE">Potential SQL/HQL Injection (Hibernate)</a> </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>CRITICAL</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>cwe</tag>
    <tag>owasp-a1</tag>
    <tag>sans-top25-insecure</tag>
    <tag>bad-practice</tag>
    <tag>sql</tag>
    <remediationFunction>CONSTANT_ISSUE</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionBaseEffort>20min</remediationFunctionBaseEffort>
  </rule>
  <rule>
    <key>S1313</key>
    <name>Using hardcoded IP addresses is security-sensitive</name>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Hardcoding IP addresses is security-sensitive. It has led in the past to the following vulnerabilities:</p>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2006-5901">CVE-2006-5901</a> </li>
  <li> <a href="http://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2005-3725">CVE-2005-3725</a> </li>
</ul>
<p>Today's services have an ever-changing architecture due to their scaling and redundancy needs. It is a mistake to think that a service will always
have the same IP address. When it does change, the hardcoded IP will have to be modified too. This will have an impact on the product development,
delivery and deployment:</p>
<ul>
  <li> The developers will have to do a rapid fix every time this happens, instead of having an operation team change a configuration file. </li>
  <li> It forces the same address to be used in every environment (dev, sys, qa, prod). </li>
</ul>
<p>Last but not least it has an effect on application security. Attackers might be able to decompile the code and thereby discover a potentially
sensitive address. They can perform a Denial of Service attack on the service at this address or spoof the IP address. Such an attack is always
possible, but in the case of a hardcoded IP address the fix will be much slower, which will increase an attack's impact.</p>
<h2>Recommended Secure Coding Practices</h2>
<ul>
  <li> make the IP address configurable. </li>
</ul>
<h2>Noncompliant Code Example</h2>
<pre>
let ip = "192.168.12.42"
let address = IPAddress.Parse(ip)
</pre>
<h2>Compliant Solution</h2>
<pre>
let ip = ConfigurationManager.AppSettings.["myapplication.ip"]
let address = IPAddress.Parse(ip)
</pre>
<h2>Exceptions</h2>
<ul>
  <li> Although "::" is a valid IPv6 address, the rule doesn't report on it. </li>
  <li> No issue is reported for 127.0.0.1 because loopback is not considered as sensitive </li>
</ul>
<h2>See</h2>
<ul>
  <li> <a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure">OWASP Top 10 2017 Category A3</a> - Sensitive Data Exposure
  </li>
  <li> <a href="https://www.securecoding.cert.org/confluence/x/qQCHAQ">CERT, MSC03-J.</a> - Never hard code sensitive information </li>
</ul>

]]></description>
    <severity>MAJOR</severity>
    <type>VULNERABILITY</type>
    <tag>owasp-a3</tag>
    <remediationFunction>CONSTANT_ISSUE</remediationFunction>
    <remediationFunctionBaseEffort>30min</remediationFunctionBaseEffort>
  </rule>
</rules>